Guide to the Rice Institute Dramatic Club records, 1917-1950 UA 035
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice Institute Dramatic Club records
1917-1950
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 035
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
The collection includes scripts from the 1920s as well as programs, ephemera, and photographs. In addition there are newsclippings and a ledger beginning in 1931 and continuing through 1934 containing lists of members, committee assignments, and minutes of meetings.
Biographical / Historical
The Dramatic Club at Rice Institute pre-dates the modern residential college sytem in which theatrical productions are often staged by colleges.
Scope and Contents
Included in the collection are scripts from the 1920s as well as programs, ephemera, and photographs. In addition there are newsclippings and a ledger beginning in 1931 and continuing through 1934 containing lists of members, committee assignments, and minutes of meetings.
Access restrictions
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition information
Gift of the Dramatic Club, September 1979
Index Terms
Subjects
College students -- Texas; Theatrical productions; Theater; Universities and colleges
Document Types
clippings (information artifacts); scrapbooks; programs (documents); typescripts
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University
- Series I: Albums, 1921-1924; 223234
  - Album of programs and photographs, 1921-1922; 111962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Album of programs and photographs, 1922-1924; 111963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: Scripts, newsclippings and programs, 1917-1950; 223235
  - Ledger: minutes and news clippings, 1931-1934; 111964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Script: Importance of Being Earnest, 111968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Script: Billeted, 111969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Script: Bird in Hand, 111970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Script: You and I, 111971 (Bin 1, Folder 7)
  - Script: Aren't We All, 111972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Script: The Romantic Age, 111973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Brain Trust newsclips, 1917; 111974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Programs and ephemera, 1921-25, 1929, 1932, 1935, 1937-40, 1947, 1949-50; 111975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Typescript: Horses, 111976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Typescript: The Nursery - Maid of Heaven, 111977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Typescript: Alice and Humpty Dumpty, 111978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Typescript: Richard Whitting and His Cat, 111979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Typescript: Double Demon, 111980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - News clippings, 1920-1941; 111981 (Box 1, Folder 17)